<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posh-IBWAPI on Adventures in Tech</title>
    <link>https://www.dvolve.net/categories/posh-ibwapi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posh-IBWAPI on Adventures in Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.dvolve.net/categories/posh-ibwapi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Infoblox Discovery for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/09/hacking-infoblox-discovery-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/09/hacking-infoblox-discovery-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>An IPAM solution is not very useful unless it accurately reflects the state of your network. The discovery features in NIOS have always been one of the great benefits of having Infoblox DDI. Network Insight and NetMRI focus on discovery of network gear and what is connected to it. The vDiscovery feature adds the ability to discover virtual infrastructure in both public and private cloud environments. All of these working together can give you a super accurate picture of what exists on your network&amp;hellip;if all your gear is supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-IBWAPI 3.1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/posh-ibwapi-3.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/posh-ibwapi-3.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-IBWAPI release, version 3.1.0. There is now an -OverrideTransferHost switch in Send-IBFile and Receive-IBFile. But to understand what it does requires a bit of explanation on how file transfers work under the hood with the Infoblox WAPI. Any given file transfer (up or down) is a 3-step process that can be generalized as follows.
 Inform WAPI that you want to do a file transfer and it returns a token and a URL to actually transfer against.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-IBWAPI 3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/04/posh-ibwapi-3.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/04/posh-ibwapi-3.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-IBWAPI release, version 3.0.0. It has only been two days since 2.0.0, but I goofed and shipped 2.0.0 with some breaking changes that I ended up reverting. The biggest feature of the release is the new file upload/download wrappers, Send-IBFile and Recieve-IBFile. They allow you to more easily do things like upload a certificate or download a grid backup and fill a functionality gap that has been bugging me since 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>