<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Active Directory on Adventures in Tech</title>
    <link>https://www.dvolve.net/categories/active-directory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Active Directory on Adventures in Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.dvolve.net/categories/active-directory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Let&#39;s Encrypt for Active Directory Domain Controller Certificates</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/using-lets-encrypt-for-active-directory-domain-controller-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/using-lets-encrypt-for-active-directory-domain-controller-certificates/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to setup an HTTPS website in the past couple years, you&amp;rsquo;ve most likely heard of Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt which is arguably the largest public certificate authority in the world. Not only are their certificates free, the entire ordering and renewal process can be completely automated using a recently finalized protocol standard known as ACME (RFC 8555).
But there are endless apps and services other than HTTP based web sites that can also use TLS certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditing Active Directory Passwords With PwnedPassCheck</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/auditing-active-directory-passwords-with-pwnedpasscheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/auditing-active-directory-passwords-with-pwnedpasscheck/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I introduced a new PowerShell module called PwnedPassCheck. It can be used to check passwords and hashes against a list of over half a billion compromised passwords exposed in data breaches thanks to Troy Hunt&amp;rsquo;s incredibly useful haveibeenpwned.com. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to use the module in conjunction with Michael Grafnetter&amp;rsquo;s amazing DSInternals module to quickly audit existing passwords in Active Directory against the compromised list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround For AD PSDrive Bug In Server 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/07/workaround-for-ad-psdrive-bug-in-server-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/07/workaround-for-ad-psdrive-bug-in-server-2019/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Until Microsoft fixes the bug with the AD PSDrive provider, use the fully qualified PSPath to the object instead of the &amp;ldquo;AD:&amp;rdquo; PSDrive path like this:
$DN = (Get-ADUser jdoe).distinguishedName $objectPath = &amp;#34;Microsoft.ActiveDirectory.Management.dll\ActiveDirectory:://RootDSE/$DN&amp;#34; Get-Acl -Path $objectPath The Story I was browsing r/PowerShell recently and came across a thread from someone who had run into a PowerShell bug after upgrading to Windows Server 2019 (1809). The user was attempting to run Get-Acl against an AD object using the object&amp;rsquo;s distinguished name like this:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>