<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>powershell on Adventures in Tech</title>
    <link>https://www.dvolve.net/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in powershell on Adventures in Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.dvolve.net/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.17.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/10/posh-acme-3.17.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/10/posh-acme-3.17.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.17.0. The highlight of this release is the ability to import or export the private key associated with an ACME account. When creating a new account or performing a key rollover for an existing account, Posh-ACME will normally generate a new random private key automatically. But you now have the option to import an existing key instead of having one generated. It works like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-IBWAPI 3.2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/09/posh-ibwapi-3.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/09/posh-ibwapi-3.2.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-IBWAPI release, version 3.2.0. There is now a ProfileName parameter associated with all of the public functions that have connection specific parameters such as WAPIHost, WAPIVersion, and Credential. This should make it easier to change profiles on a per-call basis instead of needing to run Set-IBConfig to switch away and back again.
You might use this to make it easier to compare data between different grids. You could also use this to setup some protection against accidental mistakes if you create both an &amp;ldquo;admin&amp;rdquo; profile and a &amp;ldquo;readonly&amp;rdquo; profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Infoblox Discovery for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/09/hacking-infoblox-discovery-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/09/hacking-infoblox-discovery-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>An IPAM solution is not very useful unless it accurately reflects the state of your network. The discovery features in NIOS have always been one of the great benefits of having Infoblox DDI. Network Insight and NetMRI focus on discovery of network gear and what is connected to it. The vDiscovery feature adds the ability to discover virtual infrastructure in both public and private cloud environments. All of these working together can give you a super accurate picture of what exists on your network&amp;hellip;if all your gear is supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.16.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/08/posh-acme-3.16.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/08/posh-acme-3.16.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.16.0. The highlight of this release is Preferred Chain support which is an advanced but important feature with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&amp;rsquo;s impending root transition. When you download a certificate from an ACME server, you also get the issuing chain with that certificate. But for certificate authorities with complex issuance hierarchies, the ACME server may have multiple valid hierarchies to choose from. This new feature allows you to specify which chain to use based on the Common Name of an issuing CA in the chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME.Deploy 1.1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/06/posh-acme-deploy-1.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/06/posh-acme-deploy-1.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME.Deploy release, version 1.1.0. There is now a Set-ExchangeCertificate function thanks to Erik Nemchik (@nemchik). It requires the Microsoft.Exchange.Management.PowerShell snap-in and has been tested successfully against Exchange 2019, but may work against earlier versions as well.
Updated versions can be found in the PowerShell Gallery or GitHub. Installation instructions are in the Readme.
Changelog  Added Set-ExchangeCertificate  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.15.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/06/posh-acme-3.15.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/06/posh-acme-3.15.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.15.0. The big news in this release is External Account Binding (EAB) support which widens Posh-ACME&amp;rsquo;s compatibility with certificate authorities other than Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt. Sectigo, for example, offers paid certificates and ACME compatible endpoints. However, creating the ACME account requires linking it against an existing Sectigo account using new parameters in New-PAAccount. These parameters are a standard part of the ACME protocol, but optional to implement by a certificate authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DnsClient-PS 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/06/dnsclient-ps-1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/06/dnsclient-ps-1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a brand new module called DnsClient-PS. It&amp;rsquo;s a cross-platform DNS client for PowerShell utilizing the DnsClient.NET library. In the library author&amp;rsquo;s own words:
 DnsClient.NET is a simple yet very powerful and high performant open source library for the .NET Framework to do DNS lookups. It can be used in any kind of application to query the network&amp;rsquo;s DNS server or any other DNS server even on non-default ports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.14.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/05/posh-acme-3.14.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/05/posh-acme-3.14.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.14.0. There&amp;rsquo;s now a Hetzner plugin thanks to a submission by Franz Mueller (@derguterat). The RFC2136 has an important fix when using it with names other than the root domain. The Google DNS plugin and the Azure usage guide also got a couple fixes.
Updated versions can be found in the PowerShell Gallery or GitHub. Installation instructions are in the Readme.
Changelog  Added new DNS plugin Hetzner (Thanks @derguterat) Fix for Google DNS plugin to ignore private zones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.13.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/04/posh-acme-3.13.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2020/04/posh-acme-3.13.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.13.0. There are a whole bunch of new plugins in this release and a whopping four of them were submitted by Anton Samsonov (@WiZaRd31337). One of the other big additions is the long-awaited RFC2136 plugin which utilizes BIND&amp;rsquo;s nsupdate utility to perform dynamic DNS updates. If you&amp;rsquo;re on Windows, definitely check the usage guide if you plan to use this because you likely need to download and install the nsupdate prerequisite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Let&#39;s Encrypt for Active Directory Domain Controller Certificates</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/using-lets-encrypt-for-active-directory-domain-controller-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/using-lets-encrypt-for-active-directory-domain-controller-certificates/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to setup an HTTPS website in the past couple years, you&amp;rsquo;ve most likely heard of Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt which is arguably the largest public certificate authority in the world. Not only are their certificates free, the entire ordering and renewal process can be completely automated using a recently finalized protocol standard known as ACME (RFC 8555).
But there are endless apps and services other than HTTP based web sites that can also use TLS certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME.Deploy 1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/posh-acme-deploy-1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/posh-acme-deploy-1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new module called Posh-ACME.Deploy. It&amp;rsquo;s an optional companion module for Posh-ACME that provides a set of functions to make it easier to deploy the certificates you create.
Deploying certificates is never as simple as you want it to be particularly on Windows. Some apps want PEM files in a folder referenced in a config file. Others reference them from the registry. Some need the certificates in a Windows certificate store, but they might be configured based on thumbprint via WMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.12.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/posh-acme-3.12.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/12/posh-acme-3.12.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.12.0. The Set-PAOrder function now has -DnsPlugin and -PluginArgs parameters which should make it easier to change DNS providers and/or provider parameters without needing to wait for a certificate renewal. The BouncyCastle library has been updated to the latest 1.8.5 version and the DLL file is using a non-standard name to avoid conflicts with other software that uses BouncyCastle and chooses to install the DLL into the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.11.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/11/posh-acme-3.11.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/11/posh-acme-3.11.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.11.0. The Install-PACertificate function now has optional parameters that allow you to specify the Windows certificate store location and name in case the defaults (LocalMachine\My) aren&amp;rsquo;t what you need. You can also use the -NotExportable switch to mark the certificate as non-exportable. There&amp;rsquo;s also a new function called Revoke-PAAuthorization which is mostly useful for testing a new configuration. It allows you to revoke one or more existing authorizations associated with an account so that when you generate a new certificate, the ACME server will require a full re-validation for those names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.10.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/11/posh-acme-3.10.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/11/posh-acme-3.10.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.10.0. There&amp;rsquo;s a critical fix in this version for a problem introduced by a recent change in Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&amp;rsquo;s ACME implementation that breaks renewals. A new DNS plugin for HurricaneElectric was added and the Azure plugin now supports certificate based authentication in addition to the existing methods. There&amp;rsquo;s also additional guidance in the tutorial on renewals and deployment.
Updated versions can be found in the PowerShell Gallery or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.9.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/10/posh-acme-3.9.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/10/posh-acme-3.9.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.9.0. There&amp;rsquo;s a new DNS plugin for UnoEuro thanks to a user submission. The Cloudflare plugin was also updated to support limited use tokens that don&amp;rsquo;t have edit permissions to all zones on an account.
Updated versions can be found in the PowerShell Gallery or GitHub. Installation instructions are in the Readme.
Changelog  Added new DNS plugin UnoEuro (Thanks @OrKarstoft) Fix for Cloudflare plugin not working properly when limited scope token didn&amp;rsquo;t have at least read permissions to all zones on an account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-IBCLI 1.3.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/10/posh-ibcli-1.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/10/posh-ibcli-1.3.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-IBCLI release, version 1.3.0. It adds new functions called Get-IBCLIApacheCert and Set-IBCLIApacheCert which wrap the set apache_https_cert command added in NIOS 8.4. What&amp;rsquo;s funny is that the only reason I found out about the command is because of a problem I ran into while testing Posh-IBWAPI&amp;rsquo;s new file upload functions.
The file I was trying to upload was a certificate for the web UI and I figured my test procedure would involve uploading my cert and then re-generating a self-signed cert before repeating the test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.8.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/09/posh-acme-3.8.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/09/posh-acme-3.8.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.8.0. Set-PAOrder now supports modifying some order properties that don&amp;rsquo;t require generating a new order such as FriendlyName, PfxPass, and the Install switch. If the order has already been completed, changes to FriendlyName and PfxPass will generate new versions of the associated PFX files with the updated values. But changes to the Install switch will only affect future renewals. The GoDaddy plugin will no longer fail on large accounts with more than 100 domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.7.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/09/posh-acme-3.7.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/09/posh-acme-3.7.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.7.0. In addition to some miscellaneous bug fixes, Submit-Renewal now has an optional -PluginArgs parameter for cases when you need to specify new values for a plugin but don&amp;rsquo;t want to create a whole new order from scratch. This is useful if your credentials change or if the type of credential you&amp;rsquo;re using is purposefully short-lived.
Updated versions can be found in the PowerShell Gallery or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-IBWAPI 3.1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/posh-ibwapi-3.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/posh-ibwapi-3.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-IBWAPI release, version 3.1.0. There is now an -OverrideTransferHost switch in Send-IBFile and Receive-IBFile. But to understand what it does requires a bit of explanation on how file transfers work under the hood with the Infoblox WAPI. Any given file transfer (up or down) is a 3-step process that can be generalized as follows.
 Inform WAPI that you want to do a file transfer and it returns a token and a URL to actually transfer against.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.6.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/posh-acme-3.6.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/posh-acme-3.6.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.6.0. This one has a bunch of new stuff including new plugins for Domeneshop, Dreamhost, EasyDNS, and freedns.afraid.org. The other big addition is a new function called Invoke-HttpChallengeListener which can be super handy for people doing HTTP challenges. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a self-contained webserver that will respond to requests for the HTTP challenges in your order so you don&amp;rsquo;t have manually deal with making the challenge files available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditing Active Directory Passwords With PwnedPassCheck</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/auditing-active-directory-passwords-with-pwnedpasscheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/auditing-active-directory-passwords-with-pwnedpasscheck/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I introduced a new PowerShell module called PwnedPassCheck. It can be used to check passwords and hashes against a list of over half a billion compromised passwords exposed in data breaches thanks to Troy Hunt&amp;rsquo;s incredibly useful haveibeenpwned.com. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to use the module in conjunction with Michael Grafnetter&amp;rsquo;s amazing DSInternals module to quickly audit existing passwords in Active Directory against the compromised list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Module: PwnedPassCheck</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/new-module-pwnedpasscheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/08/new-module-pwnedpasscheck/</guid>
      <description>Troy Hunt&amp;rsquo;s incredibly useful haveibeenpwned.com is a great way to check whether your email address and other personal information was exposed in a data breach. But it also allows you to separately check if a specific password was exposed in a breach. As of version 5, the data set contains over half a billion compromised passwords and the number of times they&amp;rsquo;ve been seen in data breaches. My PwnedPassCheck module lets you query that data easily via PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround For AD PSDrive Bug In Server 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/07/workaround-for-ad-psdrive-bug-in-server-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/07/workaround-for-ad-psdrive-bug-in-server-2019/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Until Microsoft fixes the bug with the AD PSDrive provider, use the fully qualified PSPath to the object instead of the &amp;ldquo;AD:&amp;rdquo; PSDrive path like this:
$DN = (Get-ADUser jdoe).distinguishedName $objectPath = &amp;#34;Microsoft.ActiveDirectory.Management.dll\ActiveDirectory:://RootDSE/$DN&amp;#34; Get-Acl -Path $objectPath The Story I was browsing r/PowerShell recently and came across a thread from someone who had run into a PowerShell bug after upgrading to Windows Server 2019 (1809). The user was attempting to run Get-Acl against an AD object using the object&amp;rsquo;s distinguished name like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infoblox and MS Management Permissions</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/06/infoblox-and-ms-management-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/06/infoblox-and-ms-management-permissions/</guid>
      <description>The NIOS documentation lacks great instructions for granting least-privilege access to use the various MS Management components. As a former Active Directory admin, that bugs me because people get frustrated and end up giving service accounts Domain Admin permissions just to get things working. This post will lay out the necessary permissions for each component and provide PowerShell examples on how to apply them easily.
Warning: I&amp;rsquo;ve tested these permissions and examples against NIOS 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-ACME 3.5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/06/posh-acme-3.5.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/06/posh-acme-3.5.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-ACME release, version 3.5.0. This one has an important fix due to a recent change in Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&amp;rsquo;s ACME implementation which now more strictly adheres to the recently finalized RFC 8555 spec. The Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt change is only on the staging server at the moment, but it will likely move to production soon and it breaks account creation on all previous versions of Posh-ACME.
Updated versions can be found in the PowerShell Gallery or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posh-IBWAPI 3.0.0</title>
      <link>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/04/posh-ibwapi-3.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dvolve.net/blog/2019/04/posh-ibwapi-3.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Just shipped a new Posh-IBWAPI release, version 3.0.0. It has only been two days since 2.0.0, but I goofed and shipped 2.0.0 with some breaking changes that I ended up reverting. The biggest feature of the release is the new file upload/download wrappers, Send-IBFile and Recieve-IBFile. They allow you to more easily do things like upload a certificate or download a grid backup and fill a functionality gap that has been bugging me since 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>